# GONZALO ANDRÉS RAMÍREZ

Senior Software Engineer

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Bogotá Colombia

#### **EMAIL**

gandres.ramirez@gmail.com

## **LINKS**

Github

## **SKILLS**

SQL

jQuery

MySQL

Python

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

GraphQL

ReactJs

NodeJs

Unity2D

Phaser3

#### **PROFILE**

I am a software developer with experience in Javascript, CSS, and HTML5. I worked with backend technologies like PHP, NodeJS, Python and .Net, databases like MySQL, SQLServer and MongoDB, but my strong experience is with FrontEnd technologies and some frameworks like AngularJs, React, Polymer, VueJS, NextJS, GraphQL. I worked with big and small teams on various projects for clients outside of Colombia (Razorfish, Microsoft, Google, PGA, etc.) using Scrum and Kanban methodologies. I'm passionate about videogame development using Javascript and Unity2D.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Senior Software Engineer, BoatyardX

BOGOTA

Jul 2021 — Present

Working on different startups managed by BoatyardX on different roles, specially FrontEnd, currently working with NextJs, GraphQL, Tailwind and Cypress.

#### **Senior Web Engineer, Huge Inc.**

**BOGOTA** 

Jul 2017 — Jul 2021

Working with Google:

Development Marketing Websites / SSG / Maintenance / Creation of new components / Localization / Javascript / 11ty

- Chromebook
- Chrome Enterprise
- Youtube and Keyword Blogs

#### Other projects:

- PGA Tour (Python, Postgres SQL, Javascript AWS Lambdas)

## Principal Front End Developer, Prodigious Latin America

BOGOTA

Oct 2014 - Jul 2017

Presentation Layer Engineer - I'm supporting front end layer using technologies like ReactJs, SASS (BEM), integrations with Backend teams principally using Sitecore.

#### Some Projects:

- Honda (Car build and price)
- T Mobile (marketing site)
- Choice Hotels (Full site redesign)

## **EDUCATION**

### Systems Engineer, Universidad San Martin

BOGOTA

Feb 2002 - Jul 2009

## **COURSES**

Zenva Phaser 3 Minidegree, Zenva

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

MS: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft

Feb 2016 - Mar 2016